Welcome to the urban jungle.
Zootopia is a animation, adventure, family film directed by Byron Howard.
Determined to prove herself, Officer Judy Hopps, the first bunny on Zootopia's police force, jumps at the chance to
crack her first case - even if it means partnering with scam-artist fox Nick Wilde to solve the mystery.
Judy Hopps (voice), played by Ginnifer Goodwin.
Nick Wilde (voice), played by Jason Bateman.
Chief Bogo (voice), played by Idris Elba.
Bellwether (voice), played by Jenny Slate.
Clawhauser (voice), played by Nate Torrence.
Bonnie Hopps (voice), played by Bonnie Hunt.
Zootopia (titled Zootropolis in some markets) is a 2016 American animated
buddy cop comedy film produced by Walt Disney Animation Studios.
Directed by Byron Howard and Rich Moore and written by Jared Bush and Phil
Johnston, it is the first film in the Zootopia franchise.
It features the voices of Ginnifer Goodwin, Jason Bateman, Idris Elba, Jenny
Slate, Nate Torrence, Bonnie Hunt, Don Lake, Tommy Chong, J.
Simmons, Octavia Spencer, Alan Tudyk, and Shakira.
The plot of the film follows the rabbit Judy Hopps, a rookie police officer, and the fox Nick Wilde, a con
artist, as they work together to uncover a conspiracy involving the disappearance of predators.
Zootopia premiered at the Brussels Animation Film Festival in Belgium on
February 13, 2016, and was released in the United States on March 4.
The film received positive reviews from critics, who praised
its screenplay, animation, and subject matter.
The film opened to record-breaking box office returns in several countries, and grossed
over $1 billion, making it the fourth-highest-grossing film of 2016.
Among other accolades, the film was named one of the top-ten films of 2016 by the American
Film Institute and won Best Animated Feature at the 89th Academy Awards.
A television spin-off series, Zootopia+, premiered in 2022,
and a sequel, Zootopia 2, was released in 2025.
The film explores themes of sheep, allegory, lion, hippopotamus, cartoon.
The tone is lighthearted.